/* Created and coded by Abhilash Narayan */
/* Quiz source: w3schools.com */

var quiz = { "JS" : [
	{
		"id" : 1,
		"question" : " Who developed Python Programming Language?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Wick van Rossum", 
			 "b":"Rasmus Lerdorf", 
			 "c":"Niene Stom", 
			 "d":"Guido van Rossum"}
			],
		"answer":"Guido van Rossum",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 2,
		"question" : "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "object-oriented programming", 
			 "b":"structured programming", 
			 "c":"functional programming",
			 "d":"all of the above"}
			
			],
		"answer":"all of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 3,
		"question" : "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "no", 
			 "b":"yes", 
			 "c":"machine dependent",
			 "d":"none of the above"}
			
			],
		"answer":"yes",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 4,
		"question" : "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "python", 
			 "b":"pl",
			 "c": "py",
			 "d": "p"
			}
			],
		"answer":"py",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 5,
		"question" : "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted", 
			 "b":"Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
			 "c":"Python code is only compiled",
			 "d":"Python code is only interpreted"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 6,
		"question" : "All keywords in Python are in _________",
		"options" : [
			{"a": " Capitalized", 
			 "b":" lower case",
			 "c":"UPPER CASE",
			 "d":"none of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"none of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 7,
		"question" : "What will be the value of the following Python expression 4 + 3 % 5 ?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "7", 
			 "b":"2",
			 "c":"4",
			 "d":"1"
			}
			],
		"answer":"7",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 8,
		"question" : " Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Indentation", 
			 "b":"key",
			 "c":"brackets",
			 "d":" all of the above",
			}
			],
		"answer":"Indentation",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 9,
		"question" : " Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "function", 
			 "b":"def",
			 "c":"fun",
			 "d":"define"
			}
			],
		"answer":"def",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 10,
		"question" : "Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "//", 
			 "b":"#",
			 "c":"!",
			 "d":"/*",
			}
			],
		"answer":"#",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 11,
		"question" : "What will be the output of the following Python code i = 1 /n while True: /n if i%3 == 0: break print(i) i + = 1?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "1 2 3", 
			 "b":"error",
			 "c":"1 2",
			 "d":"none",
			}
			],
		"answer":"error",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 12,
		"question" : "Which of the following functions can help us to find the version of python that we are currently working on?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "sys.version(1)", 
			 "b":"sys.version(0)",
			 "c":"sys.version()",
			 "d":"sys.version"
			}
			],
		"answer":"sys.version",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 13,
		"question" : "",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "pi", 
			 "b":"anonymous",
			 "c":"lambda",
			 "d":"none of the above",
			}
			],
		"answer":"lambda",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 14,
		"question" : "What is the order of precedence in python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Exponential, Parentheses, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction", 
			 "b":"Exponential, Parentheses, Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction",
			 "c":"Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Subtraction, Addition",
			 "d":"Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 15,
		"question" : "What will be the output of the following Python code snippet if x=1? x<<2",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "4", 
			 "b":"2",
			 "c":"1",
			 "d":"8"
			}
			],
		"answer":"4",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 16,
		"question" : "What does pip stand for python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Pip Installs Python", 
			 "b":"Pip Installs Packages",
			 "c":"Preferred Installer Program",
			 "d":"All of the mentioned"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Preferred Installer Program",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 17,
		"question" : "Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed", 
			 "b":"unlimited length",
			 "c":"all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
			 "d":"none of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"unlimited length",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 18,
		"question" : "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Every object in Python doesn’t have a unique id", 
			 "b":"In Python Id function returns the identity of the object",
			 "c":"None of the mentioned",
			 "d":"All of the mentioned"
			}
			],
		"answer":"In Python Id function returns the identity of the object",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 19,
		"question" : "Which of the following is the truncation division operator in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "|", 
			 "b":"//",
			 "c":"/",
			 "d":"%"
			}
			],
		"answer":"//",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 20,
		"question" : "How can you detect the client&rsquo;s browser name?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "navigator.appName", 
			 "b":"browser.name",
			 "c":"client.navName"
			}
			],
		"answer":"navigator.appName",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 21,
		"question" : "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "factorial()", 
			 "b":"print()",
			 "c":"speed()",
			 "d":"sqrt()"
			}
			],
		"answer":"print()",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 22,
		"question" : "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Every object doesn’t have a unique id", 
			 "b":"Id returns the identity of the object",
			 "c":"All of the mentioned",
			 "d":"none of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Id returns the identity of the object",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 23,
		"question" : " What will be the output of the following Python function? min(max(False,-3,-4), 2,7)",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "-4", 
			 "b":"-3",
			 "c":"2",
			 "d":"false"
			}
			],
		"answer":"false",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 24,
		"question" : "Which module in the python standard library parses options received from the command line?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "getarg", 
			 "b":"getopt",
			 "c":"main",
			 "d":"os"
			}
			],
		"answer":"true",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 25,
		"question" : "The process of pickling in Python includes ____________?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "conversion of a Python object hierarchy into byte stream", 
			 "b":"conversion of a datatable into a list",
			 "c":" conversion of a byte stream into Python object hierarchy",
			 "d":"conversion of a list into a datatable"
			}
			],
		"answer":"conversion of a Python object hierarchy into byte stream",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	}
	]
}



var quizApp = function() {

	this.score = 0;		
	this.qno = 1;
	this.currentque = 0;
	var totalque = quiz.JS.length;

	
	this.displayQuiz = function(cque) {
		this.currentque = cque;
		if(this.currentque <  totalque) {
			$("#tque").html(totalque);
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#next").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
	
			
			$("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);	
			 $("#question-options").html("");
			for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
			  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
		
				$("#question-options").append(
					"<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
					"<label class='form-check-label'>" +
							  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option'   id='q"+key+"' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
								  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
							 "</span></label>"
				);
			  }
			}
		}
		if(this.currentque <= 0) {
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", true);	
		}
		if(this.currentque >= totalque) {
				$('#next').attr('disabled', true);
				for(var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
					this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
				}
			return this.showResult(this.score);	
		}
	}
	
	this.showResult = function(scr) {
		$("#result").addClass('result');
		$("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr  + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
		for(var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
			var res;
			if(quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
					res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
			} else {
				res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
			}
			$("#result").append(
			'<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
			'<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
			'<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
			
			'</div>' 
			
			);
			
		}
	}
	
	this.checkAnswer = function(option) {
		var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
		option = option.replace(/\</g,"&lt;")   //for <
		option = option.replace(/\>/g,"&gt;")   //for >
		option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")

		if(option ==  quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
			if(quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
		}
		} else {
			quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
		}
		
	}	
	 
	this.changeQuestion = function(cque) {
			this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
			this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);	
			
	}
	
}


var jsq = new quizApp();

var selectedopt;
	$(document).ready(function() {
			jsq.displayQuiz(0);		
		
	$('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function(e) {

			//var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
			$(this).prop("checked", true);
				selectedopt = $(this).val();
		});
		
			
			 
	});

	
	
	
	$('#next').click(function(e) {
			e.preventDefault();
			if(selectedopt) {
				jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
			}
			jsq.changeQuestion(1);
	});	
	
	$('#previous').click(function(e) {
		e.preventDefault();
		if(selectedopt) {
			jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
		}
			jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
	});	



